# Nasreen Arif

(757)-957-9144

nasreen arif@live.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/nasreen-arif-b453157b/

### **Summary**

Mid-level software development professional with more than six years of experience. Detail-oriented individual with a master's in computer science, looking for a software developer position in a fast-growing company to utilize my technical skills and working knowledge of software applications, development, and design.

### **EDUCATION**

### Old Dominion University (Norfolk, VA)

**August 2021 – Present** 

Master of Science in Computer Science

# S. S. University of Engineering & Technology

**January 2011 – Dec 2014** 

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### **Old Dominion University**

August 2021 - Present

#### **Graduate Teaching Assistant**

- Graduate Teaching Assistant for CS462/562 (Cybersecurity & Fundamental)
- Graduate Teaching Assistant for CS150 Problem Solving and Programming I (C++)
- Blackboard and Canvas learning management system
- Instructor in the lab of Problem Solving and Programming I(C++)
- Grade Cyber Security related assignments, discussion board, and term paper
- Grade C++ related assignments, exercise and labs

### **Techlogix**

#### **Principal Software Engineer**

Sept 2019 - Aug-2021

- Using agile development, developed the product of sales and distribution
- The implementation of different modules, their development, and their implementation
- I was responsible to give the demos to the client

#### Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2017 - Aug-2019

- Using agile development, develop a Smart Advance product from scratch
- Integrated web-based services into software for distribution via on-premises and cloud-based deployments
- Responsible to create a roadmap and strategy for product development and technology deployment

TPS (Pvt) Ltd Dec 2015 – Oct-2017

### **Software Engineer**

- Develop proofs of concept for creative new solutions
- Implemented enhancement feature requests to enhance product functionality and extend performance
- Documented technical specifications and project testing methods for future reference

# Generic Solution & Consultancy

Dec 2014 - Dec 2015

# Software Engineer

- Increased productivity by improving software development processes and implement optimization techniques
- Analyzed solutions and coding fixes for software problems

#### **Software Internship:**

- I was responsible to resolve customer issues by establishing workarounds and solutions to debug and create defect fixes
- I was responsible to identify the issues with software processes and implement the optimization techniques that result in increased productivity

#### **SKILLS**

- Languages: C#, C++, Python, JavaScript, PHP
- Technologies: .NET Framework, ASP.NET, AngularJS, Angular, React, Node.js
- Development Tools: Visual Studio, VS code, XAMP, Postman, Bit Bucket
- **Databases:** MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server
- Operating System: Windows, Linux, iOS
- Management: GitHub, Jira, Confluence, SQL Server Management Studio
- **Search Engine:** Elastic Search

#### **AWARDS**

- \$5,000 Dr. Irwin B. Levinstein Scholarship award at Old Dominion University, 2022
- ACM Capital Region Celebration of Women in Computing (CAPWIC) Scholar, 2022

#### **CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS**

• Presented the research project titled "The Data Science in Action: The Impact of Vaccination and Age on COVID-19 Cases and Deaths" at the ACM Capital Region Celebration of Women in Computing (CAPWIC), 2022

#### **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES**

Served as a Category Judge in the computer science at the Virginia State Science and Engineering Fair (VSSEFF), 2022

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- The Complete Pandas Bootcamp 2022: Data Science with Python
- Agile Estimation & Planning Certification
- Microsoft Certification (70 480) Professional HTML5, CSS3 & JavaScript
- Conducted .NET Workshop for undergraduate students